A motivated full stack developer with 5+ years of experience and passion for technology and software development. Likes to work with *Object-Oriented Programming languages*, with a preference to Java. Good in data structures and algorithms.

Skills:

Java 8, Python, Spring Boot, Microservices, Amazon Web Services, Javascript, Vue, IOT, REST API, Git, Oracle and Postgres Database, Machine Learning, Deep Learning

Employment:

Senior Software Engineer

Xoriant Corporation

Since June 2020

- Migrate SOAP services to REST microservices using Spring Boot.
- Worked on AWS lambda services, along with EC2 and ECS services.
- CI/CD pipeline development for new services using docker, ECS, Jenkins and terraform.
- AWS SQS and SNS services with Kafka and Kinesis.
- REST API authentication development for new services using JWT (Json Web Token).

Senior Software Engineer

Intelizign Engineering Services

April 2018 - Dec 2019

- Worked on MindSphere Application Platform which provides a managed Platform as a Service (PaaS) to host applications directly on MindSphere.
- Worked on IOT Time Series Service: Used to create, read, update, and delete dynamic time series data
- Worked on AWS services like SQS, AWS lambda, Cognito, IAM, S3, EC2 instances, Docker, Serverless computing
- Deployed AWS serverless apps (lambdas).

Software Engineer

Mphasis Itd.

April 2015 - March 2018

- Developed RESTful web services at backend.
- Applying agile methodologies and Test Driven Development (TDD) for project.
- Learned about banking and shares domain in a project.
- Developed Bamboo plugin for automation of deployment process in Pivotal Cloud Foundry (PCF).

Web Developer

Futurica Technologies

December 2014 - April 2015

- Designed products display page with functionality like paging and sorting similar to e-commerce website.
- Developed web pages and made them interactive as per customer requirement.
- Designed lucky draw game on web page.
- Implemented login functionality with facebook SDK and normal login.

EDUCATION

Pune

University of Pune

July 2010 - May 2014

• B.E. in Electronics and Telecommunication, July 2014. Percentage: 61.12

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE AND AWARDS

- First Prize, Blackout Coding: Won first prize in programming competition based on C.
- Participation in Data structure and algorithm-based competitions.

Languages and Technologies

- Java 8; Python; PHP; SQL; PLSQL; JavaScript; NodeJS, VueJS
- IntelliJ; Eclipse IDE; Oracle DB; Websphere; Spring Boot; Hibernate; Tomcat; Micro Services, Amazon Web Services (AWS), TDD (Test Driven Development)